<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">GHI Project Team</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName ref="http://d-nb.info/gnd/5015376-6">German Historical Institute
                        Washington</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Washington, D.C.</pubPlace>
                <idno>
                    <idno type="DTAID">ghdi:about-team</idno>
                    <idno type="DTADirName">team</idno>
                    <idno type="shelfmark">ghdi/901:about-team</idno>
                </idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <classCode scheme="http://germanhistorydocs.org/docs/#genre">about</classCode>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div n="2">
                <p>
                    <hi rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> (GHDI) is the
                    product of close cooperation between the <ref target="editors">editors</ref> and
                    the GHI-based project team, whose members are listed below in alphabetical
                    order. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Daniel Burckhardt</head>
                <p> Technical developer Daniel Burckhardt designed the GHDI backend, integrated the
                    search engine, implemented the presentation layer, and developed the TEI schema.
                    At the GHI, Daniel works on <hi rendition="#i"><ref
                            target="https://germanhistory-intersections.org/">German History
                            Intersections</ref></hi> and <hi rendition="#i"><ref
                            target="https://www.migrantconnections.org/">Migrant
                        Connections</ref></hi>, as well as other digital history initiatives. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Katharina Hering</head>
                <p> Digital project librarian Katharina (Katja) Hering is responsible for collection
                    management (Collective Access), bilingual thesaurus development, and rights and
                    reproduction research and administration. She also supports the GHDI editorial
                    program and is the contact person for digital maps. Katja also works on <hi
                        rendition="#i">German History Intersections</hi> and <hi rendition="#i"
                        >Migrant Connections</hi> and edits the GHI’s digital history blog <hi
                        rendition="#i"><ref target="https://href.hypotheses.org/">href</ref></hi>.
                </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Simone Lässig</head>
                <p> Simone Lässig is the director of the GHI and, as such, the leader of the GHDI
                    project team. She is a cultural and social historian of the nineteenth and
                    twentieth centuries. Her research focuses on the history of knowledge,
                    migration, memory cultures and memory politics, digital history, and educational
                    media. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Insa Kummer</head>
                <p> Insa Kummer has been managing the project since May 2023. She coordinates the
                    GHI-based project team and works with sponsors, partners, volume editors,
                    freelancers, and other external contributors on all aspects of the editorial
                    program. Insa also co-managed the <hi rendition="#i">German History
                        Intersections</hi> project. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Elisabeth Mait</head>
                <p> Elisabeth Mait supported GHDI by transcribing textual sources in German script
                    and <hi rendition="#i">Fraktur</hi>, by digitizing sources and preparing them
                    for TEI markup, and by proofreading texts. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Kelly McCullough</head>
                <p> Kelly McCullough is the founding project manager of GHDI. She led the GHI-based
                    project team from 2003 until April 2023. Kelly also co-manages the <hi
                        rendition="#i">German History Intersection</hi> project and manages the
                    GHI’s book series with Cambridge University Press. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Josh Seale</head>
                <p> Josh Seale was a GHDI project contributor in 2021–2022, during which time he
                    supported the editorial program as a copyeditor, translator, proofreader, and
                    researcher. He also digitized texts and prepared them for TEI markup. </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
