<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Sponsors and Partners</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName ref="http://d-nb.info/gnd/5015376-6">German Historical Institute
                        Washington</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Washington, D.C.</pubPlace>
                <idno>
                    <idno type="DTAID">ghdi:about-partners</idno>
                    <idno type="DTADirName">about</idno>
                    <idno type="shelfmark">ghdi/903:about-partners</idno>
                </idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <classCode scheme="http://germanhistorydocs.org/docs/#genre">about</classCode>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p> GHDI is an initiative of the <ref target="https://www.ghi-dc.org/">German Historical
                    Institute, Washington DC</ref>. The project was undertaken in collaboration with
                the <ref target="https://www.ghi-dc.org/about-us/friends-of-the-ghi">Friends of the
                    German Historical Institute</ref>, and with significant support from a select
                group of sponsors and partners to whom we express our sincere thanks. </p>

            <p> The technical infrastructure of the revised and expanded second edition of <hi
                    rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> was supported by a
                generous three-year grant from the <ref target="https://www.dfg.de/en/">Deutsche
                    Forschungsgemeinschaft</ref> (DFG) through its “Infrastructure for Electronic
                Publications and Digital Science Communication” program in the area of “Scientific
                Library Services and Information Systems.” A similarly generous grant from the <ref
                    target="https://www.zeit-stiftung.de/en/">ZEIT-Stiftung Ebelin und Gerd
                    Bucerius</ref> supported the editorial work program of the second edition. </p>

            <p> The <ref target="https://maxkadefoundation.org/">Max Kade Foundation, New
                York</ref>, supported the first edition of the project with a generous multi-year
                grant that enabled the first beginnings of <hi rendition="#i">German History in
                    Documents and Images</hi>. The ZEIT-Stiftung Ebelin und Gerd Bucerius was also a
                key sponsor of the first edition. </p>

            <p> Additionally, we would like to thank our longstanding partner, the <ref
                    target="https://www.bpk-bildagentur.de/">bpk-bildagentur</ref>, for many years
                of collegiality and cooperation. We are likewise grateful to our newer partner, the
                    <ref target="https://www.dhm.de/en/collection/photo-service/">Photo service of
                    the Deutsches Historisches Museum</ref>, for the excellent collaboration on the
                second edition of GHDI. We thank Prof. Andreas Kunz of <ref
                    target="https://www.ieg-maps.de/">IEG-Maps</ref> and Dr. Cherie Norton of <ref
                    target="http://mapmakers.com/">Mapping Solutions</ref> for designing original
                maps for the first edition of GHDI. We are also grateful to cartographer <ref
                    target="https://mossmaps.net/">Dr.
                    Gabriel Moss</ref> for his work on the second edition, specifically for revising
                our legacy maps with an eye toward Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) and
                for designing new maps as well. Finally, for their essential support throughout the
                whole of the project’s history, we thank our colleagues at the <ref
                    target="https://www.maxweberstiftung.de/en/about-us/the-foundation/organisation/central-office.html"
                    >Central Office of the Max Weber Foundation </ref>. </p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
