<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Project History</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName ref="http://d-nb.info/gnd/5015376-6">German Historical Institute
                        Washington</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Washington, D.C.</pubPlace>
                <idno>
                    <idno type="DTAID">ghdi:about</idno>
                    <idno type="DTADirName">about</idno>
                    <idno type="shelfmark">ghdi/900:about</idno>
                </idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <classCode scheme="http://germanhistorydocs.org/docs/#genre">about</classCode>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>
                <hi rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> (GHDI) was conceived
                in 2002 by a small group of German- and American-born historians who sought to make
                a large collection of German historical documents available online in German and
                English translation. Modeled on other early websites such as the “Internet History
                Sourcebooks,” GHDI aimed to provide free and easy access to a broad range of sources
                needed for historical research and academic teaching. Whereas other sites of its
                generation focused on digitizing existing collections, GHDI aimed from the start to
                create a new corpus of primary sources accompanied by critical commentaries. </p>

            <p> In 2003, the project’s organizers received a multi-year founding grant from the <ref
                    target="https://maxkadefoundation.org/">Max Kade Foundation, New York</ref>, and
                a generous supplementary grant from the <ref
                    target="https://www.zeit-stiftung.de/en/">ZEIT-Stiftung Ebelin und Gerd
                    Bucerius</ref>. With funding in place, the organizers then chose as <ref
                    target="editors#first-edition">editors</ref> a small group of well-known
                historians of Germany, none of whom had previously participated in a “born digital”
                project. The original version of <hi rendition="#i"><ref
                        target="https://germanhistorydocs.ghi-dc.org/?language=english">German
                        History in Documents and Images</ref></hi> was launched later that year,
                with a handful of sources that grew over time into a collection of thousands. The
                first edition, or GHDI 1.0, was declared officially complete in 2012.</p>

            <p> The first edition of GHDI (GHDI 1.0) attracted a large and varied
                audience—professors, researchers, university students, writers, and the interested
                public. It inspired roundtable discussions at the <ref
                    target="https://www.thegsa.org/sites/default/files/GSA_program_09.pdf">German
                    Studies Association conference</ref> in 2009 and the <ref
                    target="https://aha.confex.com/aha/2010/webprogram/Session3099.html">American
                    Historical Association</ref> meeting in 2010. It was awarded the <ref
                    target="https://www.historians.org/awards-and-grants/awards-and-prizes/james-harvey-robinson-prize"
                    >James Harvey Robinson Prize</ref> of the American Historical Association in
                2010. Three years later, it was the subject of an article in <ref
                    target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0008938913000642"><hi rendition="#i">Central
                        European History</hi></ref>. </p>

            <p> In 2015–16, the GHI commissioned twenty historians of Germany to review the project.
                In parallel, the GHI developed a GHDI user survey that was completed by more than
                1,000 respondents from all over the world. Additionally, the GHI convened a focus
                group of experts in German and digital history to gather feedback on the project. At
                the conclusion of this review process, the GHI decided to relaunch GHDI with two
                primary objectives in mind. The first (or technical) objective was to migrate the
                website to a new infrastructure with enhanced functionality and better long-term
                preservation prospects and to create a modern and responsive user interface. The
                second (or editorial) objective was to revise and expand the contents of GHDI to
                reflect new developments in historiography and methodology, especially the <ref
                    target="https://trafo.hypotheses.org/9619">transnational</ref> and visual turns
                in historical research and writing. The GHI was fortunate to secure two grants: one
                from the <ref target="https://www.dfg.de/en/">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</ref>
                (DFG) to support the realization of the technical work program, and one from the
                    <ref target="https://www.zeit-stiftung.de/en/">ZEIT-Stiftung Ebelin und Gerd
                    Bucerius</ref> to sponsor the editorial program. </p>

            <p> The new revised and expanded edition of GHDI (GHDI 2.0) includes virtually all of
                the sources included in the original version (in some cases, sources were removed
                when copyright permissions could not be extended). Each volume also includes a
                selection of new sources (with commentaries) chosen by the editor of the second
                edition. The <ref target="editors">editorial board for the revised edition</ref>
                includes familiar names from the first edition as well as newcomers to our project.
                All of the editors, both new and returning, reviewed their respective volumes of
                GHDI and revised them with an eye toward incorporating new media (when applicable),
                diversifying the range of perspectives on German history, and introducing a more
                complex, connected, and outward-looking Germany. </p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
