<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title type="main">Terms and Conditions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>
					<orgName ref="http://d-nb.info/gnd/5015376-6">German Historical Institute
						Washington</orgName>
				</publisher>
				<pubPlace>Washington, D.C.</pubPlace>
				<idno>
					<idno type="DTAID">ghdi:about-terms</idno>
					<idno type="DTADirName">terms</idno>
					<idno type="shelfmark">ghdi/903:about-terms</idno>
				</idno>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p/>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<langUsage>
				<language ident="eng">English</language>
			</langUsage>
			<textClass>
				<classCode scheme="http://germanhistorydocs.org/docs/#genre">about</classCode>
			</textClass>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div n="2">
				<head>Conditions of Use</head>
				<p> The source materials included in <hi rendition="#i">German History in Documents
						and Images</hi> (GHDI) are intended for individual, academic, educational,
					and non-commercial use. Each source is fully attributed and includes a DOI as
					well as a recommended citation for use in referencing the project in academic
					books and articles, term papers, and student assignments in either print or
					digital form. </p>
			</div>

			<div n="2">
				<head>Notice on Copyright</head>
				<p> GHDI includes thousands of individual sources (original texts, translations,
					images, audiovisual files) with varying ownership and copyright status. Many
					sources are in the public domain; others are under copyright protection. In some
					cases, the status is unclear; in other cases, the copyright holders could not be
					identified or reached. In each instance, the GHDI project staff has done its
					best to determine the copyright status of the source and to contact the relevant
					parties. Questions or concerns about materials published in GHDI should be
					directed to <ref target="mailto:ghdi@ghi-dc.org">ghdi@ghi-dc.org</ref>. </p>
				<p> The GHDI project staff has provided the fullest possible attribution for all of
					the sources included in the collection. Likewise, the staff has endeavored to
					include copyright information for all materials, including those in the public
					domain. If you are interested in republishing copyrighted source materials in a
					book, article, website, or other format, please make direct contact with the
					relevant rightsholder (i.e., the author, publisher, museum, etc., credited in
					the source or attribution line). The German Historical Institute, Washington DC,
					cannot grant reprint permission in instances when the copyright is held by
					others. </p>
				<p> All volume introductions, commentaries, and didactics texts included in GHDI
					were written expressly for the project and are licensed under a <ref
						target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons
						Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License (CC
						BY-NC-ND 4.0).</ref> This license allows for these texts to be republished
					(in unaltered form and with proper attribution) for academic and/or
					non-commercial purposes. English-language translations commissioned by the GHI
					of German-language documents in the public domain are also licensed under CC
					BY-NC-ND 4.0. Please use the recommended citation as a guide when republishing
					these translations. </p>
			</div>

			<div n="2" id="content-notice">
				<head>Content Notice</head>
				<p> GHDI covers topics such as war, violence, and genocide. Some sources include
					period-specific terminology and/or imagery that modern-day users may find
					offensive or even harmful. Examples include texts and images permeated by
					racist, sexist, xenophobic, colonialist, Eurocentric, ableist, and/or
					anti-LGBTQ+ thinking. Our translations into English follow the original German
					sources closely. This emphasis on historical accuracy means that translated
					texts occasionally include terms that are derogatory toward individuals or
					groups. Pronouns in the English translations are rarely gender-inclusive because
					they were rarely intended as such in the original German texts. The GHI presents
					these difficult sources because we believe in the value of intensive critical
					engagement with the past. </p>
			</div>

			<div n="2" id="contact">
				<head>Contact</head>
				<p> If you have questions or suggestions pertaining to GHDI, please contact us at
						<ref target="mailto:ghdi@ghi-dc.org">ghdi@ghi-dc.org</ref>. </p>
			</div>

			<div n="2" id="imprint">
				<head>Imprint</head>
				<p> German Historical Institute<lb/>
					 1607 New Hampshire Ave NW<lb/>
					 Washington, DC 20009-2562<lb/>
					 USA. </p>
				<p> Phone: +1.202.387.3355<lb/>
					<ref target="mailto:info@ghi-dc.org">info@ghi-dc.org</ref><lb/>
					<ref target="https://www.ghi-dc.org/">www.ghi-dc.org</ref>
				</p>
				<p> Authorized persons<lb/>
					 Simone Lässig, Director<lb/>
					 Axel Jansen, Deputy Director<lb/>
					 Sylwia Biel, Head of Administration</p>
			</div>

			<div n="2" id="data-protection">
				<head>Data Protection</head>
				<p> This is an online-service of the German Historical Institute. The <ref
						target="https://www.ghi-dc.org/privacy-policy">Privacy Policy</ref> of the
					GHI applies to the processing of all personal data arising in the course of the
					operation of this site. </p>
			</div>

			<div n="2" id="link-liability">
				<head>Liability for Links</head>
				<p> Our site contains links to external websites, over which we have no influence.
					Therefore, we cannot accept any liability for this external content. The
					respective provider or operator of the websites is always responsible for the
					content of these pages. The linked pages were inspected for possible violations
					of law at the time of the placing of the link. Illegal contents were not
					apparent when the link was created. Continuous monitoring of the contents of the
					linked web pages is not plausible where there is no actual indication of an
					infringement of the law. Upon notification of violations, we will remove such
					links immediately. </p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
