<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title type="main">Knowledge and Education</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>
					<orgName ref="http://d-nb.info/gnd/5015376-6">German Historical Institute
						Washington</orgName>
				</publisher>
				<pubPlace>Washington, D.C.</pubPlace>
				<idno>
					<idno type="DTAID">ghis:about-knowledge-and-education</idno>
					<idno type="DTADirName">knowledge-and-education</idno>
					<idno type="shelfmark">ghis/901:about-knowledge-and-education</idno>
				</idno>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p/>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<langUsage>
				<language ident="eng">English</language>
			</langUsage>
			<textClass>
				<classCode scheme="http://germanhistorydocs.org/docs/#genre">about</classCode>
			</textClass>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div n="2">
				<head>Anne Mariss</head>
				<figure facs="mariss-anne.jpg"/>
				<p> Anne Mariss is Assistant Professor of Early Modern History at the University of
					Regensburg and the author of <hi rendition="#i">Johann Reinhold Forster and the
						Making of Natural History on Cook's Second Voyage, 1772-1775</hi> (2019).
					Her work focusses on the history of science and knowledge, European expansion,
					and material culture from a global perspective. Her current project examines the
					complex and multifaceted meaning of the rosary as an object of Catholic piety. </p>
				<p><ref
						target="https://www.uni-regensburg.de/philosophie-kunst-geschichte-gesellschaft/neuere-geschichte/dr-anne-mariss/index.html"
						>www.uni-regensburg.de/philosophie-kunst-geschichte-gesellschaft/neuere-geschichte/dr-anne-mariss/index.html</ref></p>
			</div>

			<div n="2">
				<head>Christopher Neumaier</head>
				<figure facs="neumaier-christopher.jpg"/>
				<p> Christopher Neumaier is a Research Fellow at the Leibniz Center for Contemporary
					History, Potsdam, and is currently Visiting Professor for Modern Economic and
					Social History and the History of Technology at Helmut Schmidt University. He is
					the author of two books, <hi rendition="#i">Familie im 20. Jahrhundert.
						Konflikte um Ideale, Politiken und Praktiken</hi> (2019) and <hi
						rendition="#i">Dieselautos in Deutschland und den USA. Zum Verhältnis von
						Technologie, Konsum und Politik, 1949-2005</hi> (2010). He is currently
					researching the effects of digital product design on workplace demands in the
					high-tech industry from the 1970s to the present. </p>
				<p><ref target="https://zzf-potsdam.de/en/mitarbeiter/christopher-neumaier"
						>zzf-potsdam.de/en/mitarbeiter/christopher-neumaier</ref></p>
			</div>

			<div n="2">
				<head>Michael Printy</head>
				<figure facs="printy-michael.jpg"/>
				<p> Michael Printy is Head of the Humanities Group and Librarian for Western
					European Humanities at Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University. A historian
					by training, he specializes in German and European intellectual and religious
					history from the Reformation to the Enlightenment. He is the author of the <hi
						rendition="#i">Enlightenment and the Creation of German Catholicism</hi>
					(2009) and the co-editor of <hi rendition="#i">A Companion to the Catholic
						Enlightenment in Europe</hi> (2010). </p>
				<p><ref target="https://web.library.yale.edu/sd/staff/2197"
						>web.library.yale.edu/sd/staff/2197</ref></p>
			</div>

			<div n="2">
				<head>Jeffrey Zalar</head>
				<figure facs="zalar-jeffrey.jpg"/>
				<p> Jeffrey Zalar is Associate Professor of History and Ruth J. and Robert A. Conway
					Endowed Chair in Catholic Studies at the University of Cincinnati. He is the
					author of <hi rendition="#i">Reading and Rebellion in Catholic Germany,
						1770-1914</hi> (2019) as well as many book chapters and articles on
					religious and intellectual culture in the long nineteenth century. His current
					research project examines the relationship between Catholics and natural science
					in Germany from 1830 to 1914. </p>
				<p><ref
					target="https://researchdirectory.uc.edu/p/zalarjy"
					>researchdirectory.uc.edu/p/zalarjy</ref>
				</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
