<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">GHI Project Team</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName ref="http://d-nb.info/gnd/5015376-6">German Historical Institute
                        Washington</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Washington, D.C.</pubPlace>
                <idno>
                    <idno type="DTAID">ghis:about-team</idno>
                    <idno type="DTADirName">team</idno>
                    <idno type="shelfmark">ghis/900:about/002:about-team</idno>
                </idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <classCode scheme="http://germanhistorydocs.org/docs/#genre">about</classCode>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div n="2">
                <p>
                    <hi rendition="#i">German History Intersections</hi> is the product of close
                    cooperation between the <ref target="working-groups">three working groups</ref>
                    and the GHI-based project team, whose members are introduced below. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Daniel Burckhardt</head>
                <p> Technical developer Daniel Burckhardt designed the <hi rendition="#i"
                        >Intersections</hi> backend, integrated the search engine, implemented the
                    presentation layer, and developed the TEI schema. At the GHI, Daniel works on
                        <hi rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> and <hi
                        rendition="#i">Migrant Connections</hi>, as well as all other digital
                    initiatives, including the annual digital history conference. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Katharina Hering</head>
                <p> Digital project librarian Katharina (Katja) Hering is responsible for collection
                    management (Collective Access), bilingual thesaurus development, and rights and
                    reproduction research and administration. She also supports the Intersections
                    editorial program through source research and other tasks. Katja also works on
                        <hi rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> and <hi
                        rendition="#i">Migrant Connections</hi> and co-edits the <ref
                        target="https://href.hypotheses.org/">digital history blog href</ref>. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Simone Lässig</head>
                <p> GHI director Simone Lässig doubles as founder and director of the <hi
                        rendition="#i">German History Intersections</hi> project. She is a cultural
                    and social historian of the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. Her research
                    focusses on topics central to the <hi rendition="#i">Intersections</hi> project,
                    namely the history of knowledge, migration, memory cultures and memory politics,
                    digital history, and educational media. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Insa Kummer</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rendition="#i">Intersections</hi> co-manager Insa Kummer is responsible for
                    editorial work on the Migration module and for official grant reporting. Within
                    the project, she contributes to the overall editorial program by researching,
                    translating, editing, and proofreading sources. At the GHI, Insa works on <hi
                        rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> and co-edits the
                        <ref target="https://www.ghi-dc.org/publications/ghi-bulletin.html?L=0"
                        >Bulletin</ref>. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Elisabeth Mait</head>
                <p> Research Associate Elisabeth Mait supports the <hi rendition="#i"
                        >Intersections</hi> project in many ways: by completing diverse research
                    tasks, conducting metadata research, transcribing German script and Fraktur, and
                    digitizing sources and preparing them for TEI markup. Elisabeth also works on
                        <hi rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi>. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Kelly McCullough</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rendition="#i">Intersections</hi> co-manager Kelly McCullough coordinates
                    editorial work on the Germanness and Knowledge and Education modules. She
                    supports the project as a whole by overseeing contracts and outreach, and by
                    translating, editing, and proofreading sources. Kelly also manages <hi
                        rendition="#i">German History in Documents and Images</hi> and is a
                    co-editor of <ref target="https://href.hypotheses.org/">href</ref>. </p>
            </div>

            <div n="3">
                <head>Student Interns</head>
                <p> The GHI project team is grateful for the assistance of the following student
                    interns, who made especially significant contributions to the Intersections
                    project: </p>
                <p> Isabella Auerbach<lb/> Krista Bolton<lb/> Hanna Bosse<lb/> Chris Buchholz<lb/>
                    Ashley Gonik<lb/> Daniel Graham<lb/> Milena Kagel<lb/> Sandra Kastenbauer<lb/>
                    Sarah Maurer<lb/> Madeleine Miller<lb/> Laura Maria Niewoehner<lb/> Katharina
                    Weygoldt<lb/> Alexandra Witte<lb/> Emily Woessner<lb/> Thorsten Zachary </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
